In the last video, we developed
在上一段视频中
an anomaly detection algorithm.
我们推导了异常检测算法
In this video, I like to
在这段视频中
talk about the process of how
我想介绍一下
to go about developing a specific
如何开发一个
application of anomaly detection
关于异常检测的应用
to a problem and in particular
来解决一个实际问题
this will focus on the problem
具体来说
of how to evaluate an anomaly detection algorithm. In
我们将重点关注如何评价一个异常检测算法
previous videos, we've already talked
在前面的视频中 我们已经提到了
about the importance of real
使用实数评价法的重要性
number evaluation and this captures the idea that
这样做的想法是
when you're trying to develop
当你在用某个学习算法
a learning algorithm for a
来开发一个具体的
specific application, you need to
机器学习应用时
often make a lot of choices
你常常需要做出很多决定
like, you know, choosing what features to use and then so on.
比如说 选择用什么样的特征 等等
And making decisions about all
而如果你找到某种
of these choices is often much
评价算法的方式
easier, and if you have
直接返回一个数字
a way to evaluate your learning
来告诉你算法的好坏
algorithm that just gives you back a number.
那么你做这些决定就显得更容易了
So if you're trying to decide,
所以比如你要决定
you know, I have an idea for
现在有一个额外的特征
one extra feature, do I include this feature or not.
我要不要把这个特征考虑进来？
If you can run the algorithm
如果你带上这个特征
with the feature, and run the
运行你的算法
algorithm without the feature, and
再去掉这个特征运行你的算法
just get back a number that
然后得到某个返回的数字
tells you, you know, did
这个数字就直接告诉你
it improve or worsen performance to add this feature?
这个特征到底是让算法表现变好了还是变差了
Then it gives you a much better
这样 你就有了一种更好
way, a much simpler way, with which
更简单的方法
to decide whether or not to include that feature.
来确定是不是应该加上这个特征
So in order to be
为了更快地
able to develop an anomaly
开发出一个
detection system quickly, it would
异常检测系统
be a really helpful to have
那么最好能找到某种
a way of evaluating an anomaly detection system.
评价异常检测系统的方法
In order to do this,
为了做到这一点
in order to evaluate an anomaly
为了能评价一个
detection system, we're
异常检测系统
actually going to assume have some labeled data.
我们先假定已有了一些带标签的数据
So, so far, we'll be treating
所以 我们要考虑的
anomaly detection as an
异常检测问题
unsupervised learning problem, using
是一个非监督问题
unlabeled data.
使用的是无标签数据
But if you have some labeled
但如果你有一些
data that specifies what
带标签的数据
are some anomalous examples, and
能够指明哪些是异常样本
what are some non-anomalous examples, then
哪些是非异常样本
this is how we actually
那么这就是我们要找的
think of as the standard way of evaluating an anomaly detection algorithm.
能够评价异常检测算法的标准方法
So taking the
还是以
aircraft engine example again.
飞机发动机的为例
Let's say that, you know, we have some
现在假如你有了一些
label data of just a few anomalous
带标签数据
examples of some aircraft engines
也就是有异常的飞机引擎的样本
that were manufactured in the past that turns out to be anomalous.
这批制造的飞机发动机是有问题的
Turned out to be flawed or strange in some way.
可能有瑕疵 或者别的什么问题
Let's say we
同时我们还有
use we also have some non-anomalous
一些无异常的样本
examples, so some
也就是一些
perfectly okay examples.
完全没问题的样本
I'm going to use y equals 0
我用 y=0 来表示那些
to denote the normal or the
完全正常
non-anomalous example and
没有问题的样本
y equals 1 to denote the anomalous examples.
用 y=1 来代表那些异常样本
The process of developing and evaluating an anomaly
那么异常检测算法的推导和评价方法
detection algorithm is as follows.
如下所示
We're going to think of it as
我们先考虑
a training set and talk
训练样本
about the cross validation in test
交叉验证和测试集等下考虑
sets later, but the training set we usually
对于训练集
think of this as still the unlabeled
我们还是看成无标签的
training set.
训练集
And so this is our large
所以这些就是
collection of normal, non-anomalous
所有正常的
or not anomalous examples.
或者说无异常样本的集合
And usually we think
通常来讲
of this as being as non-anomalous,
我们把这些都看成无异常的
but it's actually okay even
但可能有一些异常的
if a few anomalies slip into
也被分到你的训练集里
your unlabeled training set.
这也没关系
And next we are going to
接下来我们要
define a cross validation set
定义交叉验证集
and a test set, with which
和测试集
to evaluate a particular anomaly detection algorithm.
通过这两个集合我们将得到异常检测算法
So, specifically, for both the
具体来说
cross validation test sets we're
对交叉验证集和测试集
going to assume that, you know, we
我们将假设
can include a few examples
我们的交叉验证集
in the cross validation set and
和测试集中
the test set that contain examples
有一些样本
that are known to be anomalous.
这些样本都是异常的
So the test sets say
所以比如测试集
we have a few examples with
里面的样本就是
y equals 1 that
带标签y=1的
correspond to anomalous aircraft engines.
这表示有异常的飞机引擎
So here's a specific example.
这是一个具体的例子
Let's say that, altogether, this
假如说
is the data that we have.
这是我们总的数据
We have manufactured 10,000 examples
我们有10000制造的引擎
of engines that, as far
作为样本
as we know we're perfectly normal,
就我们所知 这些样本
perfectly good aircraft engines.
都是正常没有问题的飞机引擎
And again, it turns out to be okay even
同样地 如果有一小部分
if a few flawed engine
有问题的引擎
slips into the set of
也被混入了这10000个样本
10,000 is actually okay, but
别担心 没有关系
we kind of assumed that the vast
我们假设
majority of these
这10000个样本中
10,000 examples are, you know, good and normal non-anomalous engines.
大多数都是好的 没有问题的引擎
And let's say that, you know, historically, however
而且实际上 从过去的经验来看
long we've been running on manufacturing
无论是制造了多少年
plant, let's say that
引擎的工厂
we end up getting features,
我们都会得到这些数据
getting 24 to 28
都会得到大概20个
anomalous engines as well.
有问题的引擎
And for a pretty typical application of
对于异常检测的典型应用来说
anomaly detection, you know, the number non-anomalous
异常样本的个数
examples, that is with y equals
也就是y=1的样本
1, we may have anywhere from, you know, 20 to 50.
基本上很多都是20到50个
It would be a pretty typical
通常这个范围
range of examples, number of
对y=1的样本数量
examples that we have with y equals 1.
还是很常见的
And usually we will have a
并且通常我们的
much larger number of good examples.
正常样本的数量要大得多
So, given this data set,
有了这组数据
a fairly typical way to split
把数据分为训练集
it into the training set,
交叉验证集和测试集
cross validation set and test set would be as follows.
一种典型的分法如下
Let's take 10,000 good aircraft
我们把这10000个正常的引擎
engines and put 6,000
放6000个到
of that into the unlabeled training set.
无标签的训练集中
So, I'm calling this an unlabeled training
我叫它“无标签训练集”
set but all of these examples
但其实所有这些样本
are really ones that correspond to
实际上都对应
y equals 0, as far as we know.
y=0的情况 至少据我们所知是这样
And so, we will use this to
所以 我们要用它们
fit p of x, right.
来拟合p(x)
So, we will use these 6000 engines
也就是是我们用这6000个引擎
is that p of x
也就是p 括号
one parametrized by Mu
x1 参数是μ1
1, sigma squared 1, up
σ1的平方
to p of Xn parametrized
一直到p(xn; μn, σn^2)
by Mu N sigma squared
参数是μn σn的平方
n. And so it would be these
因此我们就是要用这
6,000 examples that we would
6000个样本
use to estimate the parameters
来估计参数
Mu 1, sigma squared 1,
μ1, σ1
up to Mu N, sigma
一直到
squared N. And so that's our training
μn, σn
set of all, you know,
这就是训练集中的好的样本
good, or the vast majority of good examples.
或者说大多数好的样本
Next we will take our good
然后 我们取一些
aircraft engines and put some
好的飞机引擎样本
number of them in a cross
放一些到交叉验证集
validation set plus some number
再放一些到
of them in the test sets.
测试集中
So 6,000 plus 2,000 plus 2,000,
正好6000加2000加2000
that's how we split up our
这10000个好的样本
10,000 good aircraft engines.
就这样进行分割了
And then we also have 20
同时 我们还有20个
flawed aircraft engines, and we'll
异常的发动机样本
take that and maybe split it
同样也把它们进行一个分割
up, you know, put ten of them in
放10个到验证集中
the cross validation set and put
剩下10个
ten of them in the test sets.
放入测试集中
And in the next slide
在下一张幻灯片中
we will talk about how to
我们将看到如何用
actually use this to evaluate
这些分好的数据
the anomaly detection algorithm.
来推导异常检测的算法
So what I have
好的
just described here is a you
刚才我介绍的这些内容
know probably the recommend a
可能是一种
good way of splitting the labeled and unlabeled example.
比较推荐的方法来划分带标签和无标签的数据
The good and the flawed aircraft engines.
来划分好的和坏的飞机引擎样本
Where we use like
我们使用了
a 60, 20, 20% split for
6:2:2的比例
the good engines and we take
来分配好的引擎样本
the flawed engines, and we
而坏的引擎样本
put them just in the cross
我们只把它们放到
validation set, and just in
交叉验证集和测试集中
the test set, then we'll see in the next slide why that's the case.
在下一页中我们将讲解这样分的理由
Just as an aside, if you
顺便说一下
look at how people apply anomaly
如果你看到别人应用
detection algorithms, sometimes you see
异常检测的算法时
other peoples' split the data differently as well.
有时候也可能会有不同的分配方法
So, another alternative, this is really
另一种分配数据的方法是这样的
not a recommended alternative, but
其实我真的不推荐这么分
some people want to
但就有人喜欢这么分
take off your 10,000 good engines, maybe put 6000
也就是把10000个好的引擎分出6000个
of them in your training set
放到训练集中
and then put the same
然后把剩下的4000个样本
4000 in the cross validation
既用作交叉验证集
set and the test set.
也用作测试集
And so, you know, we like to think of the cross
通常来说我们要交叉验证集
validation set and the
和测试集当作是
test set as being completely
完全互不相同的
different data sets to each other.
两个数据组
But you know, in anomaly detection, you know,
但就像我说的 在异常检测中
for sometimes you see
有时候你会发现有些人
people, sort of, use the
会使用相同的
same set of good engines
一部分好的引擎样本
in the cross validation sets, and
用作交叉验证集
the test sets, and sometimes you
也用作测试集
see people use exactly the
并且有时候你还会发现
same sets of anomalous
他们会把同样的一些异常样本
engines in the cross validation set and the test set.
放入交叉验证集合测试集
And so, all of these are considered, you know,
总之 所有这样考虑的
less good practices and definitely less recommended.
都不是一个好的尝试 非常不推荐
Certainly using the same
把交叉验证集
data in the cross validation
和测试集数据
set and the test set, that
混在一起共用
is not considered a good machine learning practice.
确实不是一个比较好的机器学习惯例
But, sometimes you see people do this too.
但这种情况还不少见
So, given the training cross
话说回来 给出之前分好的
validation and test sets,
训练集、交叉验证集和测试集
here's how you evaluate or
异常检测算法的
here is how you develop and evaluate an algorithm.
推导和评估方法如下
First, we take the training sets
首先 我们使用训练样本
and we fit the model p of
来拟合模型p(x)
x. So, we fit, you know, all these
也就是说
Gaussians to my m
我们用所有这些高斯函数
unlabeled examples of aircraft engines,
来拟合m个无标签的飞机引擎样本
and these, I am calling them
虽然这里我称它们为
unlabeled examples, but these are
无标签的样本
really examples that we're assuming
但实际上是我们假设的
our goods are the normal aircraft engines.
都是正常的飞机引擎
Then imagine that your
然后假定你的
anomaly detection algorithm is actually making prediction.
异常检测算法作出了预测
So, on the cross validation
所以 给出交叉验证集
of the test set, given that,
或者测试集
say, test example X, think
给出某个测试样本x
of the algorithm as predicting that
假设这个算法对 p(x)<ε
y is equal to 1, p
的情况作出的
of x is less than epsilon,
预测为 y=1
we must be taking zero, if
而p(x)≥ε时
p of x is
算法作出的预测为
greater than or equal to epsilon.
y=0
So, given x, it's trying to predict, what is
也就是说 给出x的值
the label, given y equals 1 corresponding
预测出y的值 y=1对应
to an anomaly or is
有异常的样本
it y equals 0 corresponding to a normal example?
y=0对应正常样本
So given the training, cross validation, and test sets.
所以给定训练集、交叉验证集和测试集
How do you develop an algorithm?
你应该如何推导算法呢？
And more specifically, how do
或者更具体来说
you evaluate an anomaly detection algorithm?
怎样评估一个异常检测算法呢？
Well, to this whole,
为了推导算法
the first step is to take
我们的第一步是
the unlabeled training set, and
取出所有的无标签的训练样本
to fit the model p of x lead training data.
拟合出模型p(x)
So you take this, you know
虽然我说的是
on I'm coming, unlabeled training set,
无标签的训练集
but really, these are examples
但实际上这些样本
that we are assuming, vast majority
我们已经假设它们
of which are normal aircraft engines,
大多数都是正常的飞机引擎
not because they're not anomalies
是没有异常的
and it will
然后要用这些训练集
fit the model p of x. It
拟合出模型p(x)
will fit all those parameters for all
也就是用所有这些
the Gaussians on this data.
高斯模型拟合出参数
Next on the cross validation
接下来 对交叉验证集
of the test set, we're
和测试集
going to think of the anomaly
我们要让异常检测算法
detention algorithm as trying to
来对y的值
predict the value of
作出一个预测
y. So in each of like
所以 假如对我的每一个
say test examples.
测试样本
We have these X-I tests,
我们有
Y-I test, where y is
(x(i)test, y(i)test)
going to be equal to
其中y=1或0
1 or 0 depending on whether this was an anomalous example.
对应于这个样本是否是异常的
So given input x in
因此 给定测试集中的输入x
my test set, my anomaly detection
我的异常检测算法
algorithm think of it as
将作出预测
predicting the y as 1 if p of x is less than epsilon.
当p(x)小于ε时 预测y=1
So predicting that it is an anomaly, it is probably is very low.
所以 在概率值很小的时候 预测样本是异常的
And we think of the algorithm is predicting that y is equal to 0.
如果p(x)的值大于或等于ε时
If p of x is greater then or equals epsilon.
算法将预测y=0
So predicting those normal example
也就是说如果概率p(x)比较大的时候
if the p of x is reasonably large.
预测该样本为正常样本
And so we can now
所以现在
think of the anomaly detection algorithm
我们可以把
as making predictions for what
异常检测算法想成是
are the values of these y
对交叉验证集
labels in the test sets
和测试集中的y
or on the cross validation set.
进行一个预测
And this puts us somewhat more similar
这样多多少少让人感到
to the supervised learning setting, right?
和监督学习有点类似 不是吗？
Where we have label test
我们有带标签的测试集
set and our algorithm is
而我们的算法就是
making predictions on these labels
对这些标签作出预测
and so we can evaluate it you
所以我们可以通过
know by seeing how often it gets these labels right.
对标签预测正确的次数来进行评价
Of course these labels are
当然 这些标签会比较偏斜
will be very skewed because y
因为y=0
equals zero, that is normal
也就是正常的样本
examples, usually be much
肯定是比出现
more common than y equals
y=1 也就是异常样本
1 than anomalous examples.
的情况更多
But, you know, this is much closer
这跟我们在监督学习中
to the source of evaluation
用到的评价度量
metrics we can use in supervised learning.
方法非常接近
So what's a good evaluation metric to use.
那么用什么评价度量好呢？
Well, because the data is
因为数据是非常偏斜的
very skewed, because y equals 0 is
因为y=0是
much more common, classification accuracy
更加常见的
would not be a good the evaluation metrics.
因此分类准确度不是一个好的度量法
So, we talked about this in the earlier video.
我们之前的视频中也讲过
So, if you have a very
如果你有一个
skewed data set, then predicting
比较偏斜的数据集
y equals 0 all the time,
那么总是预测y=0
will have very high classification accuracy.
它的分类准确度自然会很高
Instead, we should use evaluation
取而代之的
metrics, like computing the fraction
我们应该算出
of true positives, false positives,
真阳性、假阳性、
false negatives, true negatives or
假阴性和真阴性的比率
compute the position of the
来作为评价度量值
v curve of this algorithm or
我们也可以算出查准率和召回率
do things like compute the
或者算出
f1 score, right, which is
F1-积分
a single real number way of summarizing
通过一个很简单的数字
the position and the recall numbers.
来总结出查准和召回的大小
And so these would be ways
通过这些方法
to evaluate an anomaly detection
你就可以评价你的异常检测算法
algorithm on your cross validation set or on your test set.
在交叉验证和测试集样本中的表现
Finally, earlier in the
最后一点 之前在
anomaly detection algorithm, we
异常检测算法中
also had this parameter epsilon, right?
我们有一个参数ε对吧？
So, epsilon is this threshold
这个ε是我们用来决定
that we would use to decide
什么时候把一个样本当作是
when to flag something as an anomaly.
异常样本的一个阈值
And so, if you have
所以 如果你有
a cross validation set, another way
一组交叉验证集样本
to and to choose this parameter
一种选择参数ε的方法
epsilon, would be to
就是你可以试一试
try a different, try many
多个不同的
different values of epsilon, and
ε的取值
then pick the value of epsilon
然后选出一个
that, let's say, maximizes f1
使得F1-积分的值最大的那个ε
score, or that otherwise does well on your cross validation set.
也就是在交叉验证集中表现最好的
And more generally, the way
更一般来说
to reduce the training, testing,
我们使用训练集、测试集
and cross validation sets, is that
和交叉验证集的方法是
when we are trying to make decisions,
当我们需要作出决定时
like what features to include, or
比如要包括哪些特征
trying to, you know, tune the parameter
或者说要确定参数ε取多大合适
epsilon, we would then
我们就可以
continually evaluate the algorithm
不断地用交叉验证集
on the cross validation sets and
来评价这个算法
make all those decisions like what
然后决定我们应该
features did you use, you know,
用哪些特征
how to set epsilon, use that, evaluate
怎样选择ε
the algorithm on the cross validation
所以 就是在交叉验证集中
set, and then when we've
评价算法
picked the set of features, when
然后我们选出一组特征
we've found the value of
或者当我们找到了
epsilon that we're happy with, we
能符合我们要求的ε的值后
can then take the final model and
我们就能用最终的模型
evaluate it, you know, do the
来评价这个算法
final evaluation of the algorithm on the test sets.
或者说 用测试集 来最终评价算法的表现
So, in this video, we talked
在这段视频中
about the process of how
我们介绍了
to evaluate an anomaly
如何评价一个异常检测算法
detection algorithm, and again,
同样地
having being able to evaluate
在能够评价算法之后
an algorithm, you know, with
通过一个简单的的
a single real number evaluation,
数值的评价方法
with a number like an F1 score
用一个简单的F1-积分
that often allows you to
这样你就能更有效率地
much more efficient use
在开发异常检测系统时
of your time when you are
更有效率地利用好你的时间
trying to develop an anomaly detection system.
把时间用在刀刃上
And we try to make these sorts of decisions.
我们能够作出决定
I have to chose epsilon, what features to include, and so on.
确定应该如何选取ε 应该包括哪些特征等等
In this video, we started
在这段视频中
to use a bit of labeled
刚开始我们用了一组
data in order to
带标签的数据
evaluate the anomaly detection algorithm and
目的是为了评价异常检测算法
this takes us a
这让我们感觉到
little bit closer to a supervised learning setting.
跟监督学习很相像
In the next video, I'm going
在下一节视频中
to say a bit more about that.
我们将更深入地谈到这个问题
And in particular we'll talk about when should
具体来说 我们将谈到
you be using an anomaly detection
应该如何使用异常检测算法
algorithm and when should we
以及什么时候我们应该用监督学习
be thinking about using supervised learning instead, and what are the differences between these two formalisms.
这两种算法到底有什么区别 【教育无边界字幕组】翻译：所罗门捷列夫 校对：竹二个 审核：小白_远游